Yeah, OK, thank you. So now today we actually
are learning something really important,
important, OK, um, technical countermeasure.
So cryptography algorithm, OK, uh, from
today. And then so we will discuss a different scenario and
you will see how each different crypto algorithm
can help in different scenarios, right? And then I
have included those classic crypto and the basics for the
symmetric encryption in my pre-le recording.
If you haven't watched them, please watch them,
otherwise it may be hard for you to understand why we are
here today, right? And then, so the
objective is to understand how confidentiality can be
guaranteed through our crypto algorithm,
OK? And also other features, other security goals.
We have 5 goals in total, right, CIA and
authenticity and non-repudiation, right?
And if you read that 5 goals, right, um,
We have some algorithm which can guarantee confidentiality,
including all the algorithm I'm discussing today.
And, but to guarantee the other feature,
other goals like integrity, authenticity,
and non-repudiation, we have to combine some algorithm together
and mostly would be some content we will learn next week,
OK. And you can see how those secret goals can be guaranteed.
So the case we will discuss today is the,
for example, the first one is someone wished to send a secret message to his
partner online by seeing this description.
The confidentiality is the focus for that person right here,
right? And then so the confidentiality means one
secrecy during the transmission and this algorithm can guarantee
that, right? And if we want to have the app developer.
Prove the software is a clean software, no malicious code was
attached to that software. So the case for this app
developer is to To have the integrity embedded in
those uh app, right, in those software. So the integrity
was very important. And then, so in different scenario,
always want to achieve maybe sometimes different goals,
right? So for the integrity, and we can consider another way to
guarantee the integrity. And then for a bank
system. Here for bank system and then you
can imagine the message and you want to make sure it's not
modified by a man in the middle, right? And then
So man in the middle, which is sometimes will use this,
this short term to mean the man in the middle attack,
right? And you want, you want to make sure the message was not modified.
If this is a focus, then this means integrity again.
Right? But of course, sometimes in the bank system,
you also want to make sure the transaction was from the true
sender, right? And the true sender can't,
can't deny he permitted to um
Send out some money to another receiver,
right, if he has clicked the transaction the confirm button,
right? So we want to have the non-reputation here embedded in the
bank system and also authenticity we want to
authenticate real sender, right, verify the identity of that
sender, right? So in this case, but of course if we want to have
not modified then the focus is integrated,
right? But depending on different scenario,
we actually want to guarantee uh different security goal or
combined the goal, right, for that system.
And then HR officer wants to check if a digital
certificate provided by a new employee is true or not,
right? So this HR officer, maybe the new employee said,
says, oh, he got the certificate from a university,
and he also got a certificate from Cisco,
from CISSP, a security certificate, right?
Of course, we want to check whether that certificate is a real certificate or it's a fake,
right? So how, what's the, what, what
is the purpose or secret goal here for this HR
officer? What's the secret goal if he wants to use the system to check,
and his goal is to Check the
authenticity, right, of that certificate.
Right? So he wants to also probably, um,
want to check the message. I mean, for that authenticity part of
um certificate, we also want to have the
integrity. So for example, uh the certificate of,
I mean, issuer, issuing um body, they also want
to have the integrity of the message, um.
Guaranteed or signed by themselves so that this HR
officer can know the information was correct,
right, and also was issued by a
Cisco or a university, right? So, we have those
integrity and authenticity, um, wanted to
embedded with this student certificate. And there's a way to do that.
So we will actually explore how we can utilize different algorithms so that
we have those purpose achieved, right? And also another case,
which is to check an e-signed document.
was actually from the true center. And from this description,
it's actually to again to check the authenticity,
right? And also the true sender can't deny actually from
him right and we actually wanted to have the non
reputation to be embedded with those documents because
of course the true sender. Verified his identity,
that's good. But also sometimes if he signed,
he can't deny later he didn't sign that document,
right? So we want non-repudiation as well,
uh, in such scenario for like e-signature or that kind
of um application, right? We want to have this authentication non-repudiation
embedded. So, in different cases, we want,
we want to use the right technology. To do,
to achieve the, the, the right goal, right,
for different scenario. So this is what we will focus on to learn in
this week and next week, OK. Um
Yeah, OK. I, Joyce said you can't see,
it's inverted. I don't know, but you can see me and hear me clearly,
right, for all students, OK, right? Yeah,
that's good. OK, that's good. So now I want to show
you the, the evolve, I mean the development of all this algorithm.
OK, there's a history for everything to To be built up,
OK, uh, for this cryptography world. And originally that's a classic
cryptography, which was based on substitution and transposition.
So we call that classic, and that's an actual branch.
And now people don't use that more, use that anymore because it's
not safe, um, enough, right? And then people moved to the modern
one. And the classic was used maybe more than 100 years ago in the
military field and based on the shifting and,
and substitution so that they have some code book,
right, and which was, found not, not safe anymore.
Um, in my product recording, you can see there's a frequency analysis
process and people found that the code book can be crackable.
Right, so that's why symmetric and asymmetric was were
developed later, right, for as a modern crypto.
So symmetric was developed first and then
asymmetric. So with symmetric, we will discuss all
the three, but they are also similar, um,
Basics for the stream cipher a different standard,
but, but the basic idea was that XOR operation.
OK, we explained in our pre-elect coding and we will use this to
explain how those works, OK, in different scenario,
and then we will move to asymmetry next week and this RSA and
different Hillman algorithm or the main algorithm.
I will put in my pre-lecture recording. I have already published
online and if you can do some pre-learning for those
algorithms, that would be great because on the lecture,
we will focus on the applications rather than just explain those algorithms
one more time. Um, yeah, I want to focus on application,
how those algorithms was used in reality,
and so that we can achieve different security goals.
OK? So now, um, this is a bit, a
bit probably, um. Recap
from encryption decryption based XOR operation.
So very quick and you know XOR operation would do this kind
of operation. It, it's called exclusive or.
So which means we have, if we have two A and B,
like 01 as input. If these two digits are different,
an output will always be a 1. If these two digits are the same,
output will always be a zero, OK, like 11,
0, and 000. OK, so the encryption will be based on the
bitwise XOR operation. So this is how m message
and key and XOR and we have a ciphertext.
And for decryption, we would XOR one more time with the
key and we can get the original message.
And the reason why is this key will be used twice for XOR
and which will generate a 0, so which means original message can
be um can be deduced by using this
key two times. So for encryption we do XRR
once and for decryption we use the same key.
Uh, for the ciphertext we do another type of XOR we got the original message,
right? So, um, that's the basic, uh,
fundamental knowledge for all symmetric encryption,
all symmetric encryption. So I want you to know how that works,
OK, XOR. And then now here is, uh, mode
I explained in my product recording. And then I want you now
to understand why it's simple, um, because it's based on just a simple
encryption for each block message each block of message.
Original message was chopped into identical blocks,
right? And then they will use the key to do XOR and the
site will be issued, right, if we have two
blocks the same and because the key. Is the
same, so the output will be the same because all this operation
is XOR, right? If you have original two blocks are the same and the
output should be the same. Then, um,
Then it will make some pattern data pattern maintained after
you do an XOR, right? And then for the decryption,
the same thing we would do the key XOR one more time you have the original
message obtained. So that's basically what you can see from my
previous slides, right? We just do a simple XOR,
but um. The pattern, the data pattern, if originally they are
the same and output will be the same. So by looking at the ciphertext,
maybe the ciphertext itself during the transmission is not perfectly
safe because it may have identical uh blocks,
and then we know original message will be identical.
So this can be seen by that penguin picture,
right? So this penguin picture shows um those
white block. of message and after
encrypted and these blocks are the same,
right? These blocks are the same. So you can see this penguins
pattern to be there, right? So, so it's
It, it can't hide the data patterns. So unsuitable for
long message if we're using this electronic code book mode,
right? And also, it says, um, and this is actual advantage of
this ECB mode. You can imagine the original message can be chopped into
blocks, and all these blocks can be done this XOR operation in
parallel. You're just in one time. And the cybertext is output.
So, so very quick encryption and decryption also very quick.
However, um, it's not 100% safe, right? So
in this week's workshop, you will get to do this ECB encryption
and try to see this uh encryption pattern
actually. There is a pattern
disclosed based on this penguin picture.
They will just try that encryption method.
And then We have to find some other way to encrypt.
So you will also get to practice other modes like like CBC
mode, OK, um, cipher blockchaining mode,
um, and to see this secrecy of the original message was
perfectly kept, right? Um, and there's also another
disadvantage for this ECB mode. It's susceptible for
to, um, it's susceptible to replay attacks,
right? I've already explained it in my production recording,
and if you can steal the whole message of those
encrypted input message or which was encrypted message
for your credential and password. And the whole,
the whole message can be just a uh
Stolen and then sent through to the system one more time and then so
that's why we call that replay attack and the system doesn't recognize and just
pass you to the system, right? So however,
to, to defend against this replay attack we can either add a
timestamp. So that next time when the system um got the same message,
which is the correct ciphertext based on your identity and the credential
password, and then the system would check the timestamp,
OK, if the timestamp uh embedded into the message was not
correct, then then the system wouldn't pass you.
So the timestamp would be a way to defend against this replay attack
or sometimes we have the Uh, two-way authentication
because we want to have 16 digit time code,
right, um, pop into your phone or your email and then you
have to provide the right six digit code which is 22.
Defend against this replay attack, OK? If someone has stolen the whole message,
which was your encrypted identity information,
but then it's not combined with the authentication code,
and then you still can't get into the system.
So that's the way to defend against this ECB replay attack.
Um, however, before, I mean, apart from using that one,
we have some other mode which can Um, be safer than ACB
mode, OK. So, so this mode. Which we call that
cipher block chaining mode which is actually The
fundamental technology blockchain is using right
nowadays. The blockchain is so popular nowadays,
but essentially it's a very simple idea.
It's like this, OK. So now I'll show you how this EC
CBC mode is working. Um, initially, we have to
have some initialization vector. We call that IV,
OK? To start for the first block. OK, and
then, In this CBC mode, the repeated plaintex does not lead to the
repeated ciphertext. You understand why,
because we have all this, OK, line, and which makes
the same. PlainText won't have the same ciphertext
output. And it can only be. Encrypted in
serial, in serial. So now let's look at why it can
only be encrypted in serial, not like ECB mode.
ECB mode can be done, OK, chopped into blocks and do
XOR in one go, and the ciphertext is ready,
right? But for CBC mode it's not working like that,
OK. So it is working like. The plaintext,
the first block. Will be activated with IV
number. And then there's a key to be used here,
so the ciphertext is obtained for the first block.
And then the output of this first block will be given to the next
block. And then XOR with your second block of
text, and then the output will be given to the key and the key was
applied and the 2nd output ciphertext is here
and this output was given to the 3rd block.
To do XLR with the plaintext, and then the key
is used and you got the 3rd output and then the 3rd output is given to the
4th block. So now you can see why it's in serial.
You always have to wait until your last block to finish its
encryption and then have the output and then to feed in
to the next round, right? So which is why it can only be done in
serial, the encryption. And then the speed is
much slower than ACB mode. ECB mode is a mode that we
discussed before, right? So, it can't be done in parallel.
You have to wait until each block to be done to do the next block.
And then if you have very long message and you have to encrypt block by block,
and then the speed is very slow here for,
for a CBC mode compared with ECB mode. However,
the good part is the repeated plaintext does not,
does not lead to the repeated ciphertext.
You can see this plaintext or that plaintext if they are the
same, but which doesn't mean this feed in from last
round will be the same, right? So the output ciphertext,
this one and that one wouldn't be the same.
Right, so which makes sure those patterns won't be
leaked. So which is why when you use the CPC mode,
when you encrypt those identity blocks
having very different ciphertext and which does
not give any pattern disclosed in this CBC mode,
right? OK, I'm sorry. So,
um, this is how it works. I'll just use a very simple example to
show you how the CBC encryption is working.
Um, and then we are now having only
18 digit message, original message,
and each message, um, was chopped into
a two digit block. OK, there are 4 blocks,
OK? And then there's a key. Key is a cipher
table here, right, and then this is for encryption and we have IV
number. I give you this IV number here which is
10, OK, which is the IV number here, OK,
so which is 10, 2 digits. OK, so how it works
we firstly XOR original text with this IV number
so 00 and 10. Now you remember that
XR operation. So if you have 00 and
10, we do XOR, right? So I just type like
x here and then. The same digit
will generate a 0, right. The different digit will generate a 1.
Remember, so that's how XR is working, right?
So that's why we have 10 as the output here,
right? And then when you have the output from this XOR
operation, you will do, OK.
and you will do a key um ciphertext. So
this key is a is a cipher table. When you
have 10 as the input, you would check your
cipher table. 10 will be encrypted into 11,
OK, which is this third entry, a third entry here.
So you can check this one, right? 10 will be
encrypted into 11, which is why you get 11 here,
right. And now you have this output. Remember the output will be given
to the input for your next round, OK. So then
you have this 11 XOR with 101.
OK, 11 XR with the next round and next blocks plain
text. So 01 XR is 11. Remember the same
digit always output 0 and different digits will output a
1, so which is why you got 10 at this time.
So 11 and 01 you got 10
because same digit gets a 0 and different digit gets a 1,
right. So you've got 10 again, so you check with this cipher table,
10 will be output 11 and 11 now is given
to the next round. 11 and 10 XR,
OK? If it's 11. Here
and 10 x. Now remember the
same digit gives 0 and different digit 10 gives 1.
So which is why you have 01 here. So 01 you check the cipher
table which is this line right 01 will be encrypted into
10, which is why you have 10 here, right.
So 10 will be given to the next round. And the 111 0
XOR you got 01 OK, based on
XOR's operation and then 01 you finally got
10. OK, according to the cipher table, and then the
cipher table, which is a reversed version of your cipher
table which actually just show you, uh, when you got 00
as output originally it should be a 11, right?
When you got 00 as output originally it's,
it comes from 11, right. 0011
and 1100. So which is a reverse version of your cipher table.
So that's the key here applied, OK, which is the cipher table
and now you can also see the 01 originally it should be a 0
001 it should be a 00. So which is this line it's a
reversed one so it's got. 01 originally it should be
00. OK, so decrypted into 00 because
01 decrypted to be 00. OK, so which is just a reverse version,
OK. Now how this decryption is working is
we got to have the same IV again. Remember the same IV needs
to be shared with the receiver. If the receiver doesn't have
the same IV, the receiver can't do a proper decryption.
So this is how it works. When you got the ciphertext
transmitted to your receiver. And receiver
again use. Firstly, use a key to
do a decryption, right? When you got 11 as a
ciphertext, you want to check the decipher table what's the original
message for your 11. So 11 original should be
10 according to this table again, 11 was
from 10, that was from 10.
So originally it should be 10 and then it will XOR here
it will XOR with IV number. So XR with
IV IV is 10 so that's 10 here. So that
one when it XOR it generates
00 OK, generates 00. And then remember
when we do this decryption, we next, next block doesn't have
to wait until the first block to finish.
So it can do a decryption at the same time when you do this
round of calculation. So because that 11
here has already been given to the second round as the
input here, so The second block
starts starts with 11 and 11 here. When we check
the table 11 is originally 10, so that's the same here,
10, and you do XOR with the with the.
Ciphertext of your previous block, right,
so that's 11 xy with 10 and which gives a
01, OK. And the third block, the same thing we have the third
ciphertext which is 10 and we also according to
10 deciphertex we check which is this line.
10 original should be 01 and if you check 10 original should be the
01 so there's a second line here in the cipher table.
So original should be 01 and 01 XR with your your last
block input which is 11 and you got 10 finally.
So then you check all this deciphered or
decrypted message which is exactly the same as your original message,
right? So this is how decryption works and now I just want to
um ask you one question. Do you see?
And the decryption, can decryption be in parallel or
in serial? Now you think about this question,
right? So, does decryption has to be slow as
encryption, or it can be done in parallel?
The decryption process. So the
decryption process actually can be done in parallel
because we don't have to wait until the output
to be given from your last round, right?
So they can be done in parallel actually.
So the decryption in CBC mode can be quick.
However, the encryption has to be slow, right?
So the CDC mode encryption is slow. Um, much slower than EB
ECB mode, but Speed is A
lot faster. Right? And another thing I want you
to pay attention is the key, right? The key here must
be shared securely, I mean secretly or safely.
With the sender and receiver, right, the key must be the same,
so it's two symmetric key encryption. When we talk about a symmetric key,
we are talking about the key are the same,
right? So the key is still the same, right?
We've got to have the cipher table and decipher table which are the same,
right? We know the same key is shared and for
the CBC mode IV number needs to be.
Known by the receiver as well. If the receiver doesn't have this
IV number, and then the receiver wouldn't be able to
decrypt the message properly. And now you can imagine how
CBC is more secure than the ECB mode.
Firstly, identical original message wouldn't have the identical
output, right? That's for sure. And another thing is if we
change IV number, OK, for the same message,
the output will be totally different, right?
So if you're using a different IV number.
And the ciphertext will always be different compared
with the different uh IV was used before,
right? So, so this makes CBC mode
um more secure, actually, because the IV
number can um add some layer of security in those
encryption. So changing the IV number. Um,
and then we have made sure the encryption message won't be the same.
No, so it. It, it itself um
can prevent that replay attack, replay attack,
right? So, um Of course, um,
yeah, I mean, I mean, for, for this CBC mode.
However, we have to guarantee the IV number has to be really,
really, um, safely shared between the sender and
receiver. Otherwise, the receiver won't,
won't be able to, if he only has the key,
he doesn't have the IV number, and then this receiver can't decrypt the message,
right? So that's the CBC mode. So, that's
why I, I just draw this one so to emphasize how important
this IV number is, but also we have to guarantee there's a way to share
this IV number very uh securely, OK, in
reality, otherwise. It, it, it can't, it,
the symmetric encryption can't, can't do any like
confidentiality, um, sharing, right? OK,
so there are different modes, and in my learning activity,
I also put some output feedback mode and then they're just people are
using a way to design this process so that they have different mode
encryption and then decryption and then All of
them works right, and all of them having different advantage and disadvantages.
Some of them may be faster and some may be slower,
but most of them are all based on bitwise operation,
right, and combine this key cipher table and together,
so they are all different modes. But then if we only do just the one
time of this bitwise operation. If the IV number or
the key, the single key and IV number were disclosed,
and then this makes the symmetric encryption not safe at all,
and there is no secrecy guaranteed by this mode.
So that's why people actually design some standard which makes
this bitwise based operation. A, uh, I mean,
a very, very complicated process. So this is how they make,
right? So this is a DEX and data encryption standard,
which actually was designed, um, I mean,
more than 50 years ago. And people found only to just do once,
um, bid wise, which is not safe at all. Because the key can be
easily probably cracked, and those IV number,
which won't be very long and can be stolen in some sense,
and that, that's why people are doing this,
OK, standard to make it, to make the whole process very complicated.
I just want to, uh, I, I don't want you to memorize anything of this,
but just to understand how people make it complicated.
You can see original input. Uh, long message was chopped into
64 bits, OK, and then they will do a,
um. Left 32 bits and right 32 bits
and then left 32 bits will be output here directly but right
32 bits will be applied by a key right and then by some function,
the function can be some shifting, OK, to the left to some positions
and then, and then applied by a key after shifting and then the output
will be bitwise XOR. With left 32 bits
and then this output will be given to the right and this right
is given to the left and they swap the position and the right 32
bits is doing the same um operation as
we did before for the originally right position so that's uh
from left, right. So that operation was done by a different
key in um in this K2. And then that
output is bitwise XOR with left again and
then we swap, OK, we swap swap. So there are
16 rounds of this swapping and XOR operation,
right, 16 rounds, and in each round key is different,
key is different. And then, so this is one single
death, DES operation.
Um, so the output. Of course, the people found that that is not
safe anymore. And that's why people actually
designed the triple decks. So which is to apply that 3
times, 3 times in this picture. OK, so in this picture,
each K1 here is a set of 16 keys. OK,
16 keys in here and another 16 keys,
another 16 keys, right? So this is a triple deck and
now you can imagine with the de itself, it,
it's quite complicated already, right? So it,
it, it, it's not like very fast. Because we have
to always do this, um, permutation and XLR
in each round and we have to go through 16 rounds.
And for triple death, we have to do 48 rounds,
OK, if we do that, OK, the whole triple times together.
So the time-wise, the speed wise, the triple death must be
a lot slower than that because it has to do with that 3 times.
And then people found, oh, it's too slow.
Of course, it's a lot safer than death, and death has been corrected,
but the triple deaths is um Yeah, it, it's
still, it's still regarded as a relatively safe standard,
but it also has the risk to be uh cracked,
right? So which is why people developed AES,
which is Advanced Encryption Standard, Advanced Encryption Standard,
um, that was developed by this person. So it's,
it also has another name, right? AES. Because people are not
satisfied with the speed of that triple that,
so people want a faster encryption standard.
So that's why people designed this AES and also to make it
stronger, make it more safe, right? Than that,
than triple that and also make it faster,
OK, do not just do this round, I mean, again and again,
right? So they use uh another standard, so AES and
so here is just a, a glance for, I mean,
just a simple view, uh, which was from old Cisco encryption but which
shows how Um, this AES and compared with DES and
triple DES, a very simple view for you to see why people are moving from
DES and to triple DES and, and then AES,
right? So there are different key size and bits.
Of course, the longer key, uh, make it stronger,
hm, but you Of course, may, may affect the speed a bit,
right? So, but of course this AES has been a lot quicker
than that and triple that, right? So the time to crack,
of course, this was based on an old computer and now it may not need that
many years, especially with a quantum computer,
right? It may. Um, be less time, but still relatively,
people still use AES a lot and still consider that one is a
quite safe standard in our, uh, community.
So we still use that AES a lot. And of course,
it outperforms triple DES in security-wise.
So that's why when you look at your router,
and their option for you to choose for the encryption algorithm and AES or triple DES,
um, now you understand. There's no doubt if you have
the option, you should choose AES rather than triple DES that give you the fastest
speed and also give you better protection for your um communication
online, right? OK. So that's a for comparison and
you see the general um pre uh I mean
invention time. And then you can see all of
them are symmetric cipher, which means you have to find a way to share the
key. And if IV number is used, then you have to share the IV number as
well, and then the block size and, and how many rounds,
and that's 16 and that's 48, right? And the speed which is slow and very
slow and fast, and security wise, it has different uh option,
uh property there. So these are the application.
OK, we are using the symmetric crypto.
Um, of course, people talk about asymmetric a lot,
but which doesn't mean asymmetric can replace symmetric because symmetric
still works very fast compared with asymmetric.
The reason why symmetric crypto was based on bit-wise,
OK, bit-wise calculation. Although there's a lot of rounds to go,
but still based on bit-wise, but for asymmetric,
you will learn next week, which was based on exponential calculation,
OK, multiplication, right, multiple times and to the number of power,
some power number. And which makes it slower,
a lot slower than symmetric, which is why symmetric crypto
algorithms are widely used in
Keeping this confidentiality. You can see from the internet,
secure communication, file encryption, decryption,
and server data encryption, right? And when you
go online, you want to browse something securely and fastly and
all those symmetric crypto were used behind.
And then the bank sector payment application and all this
um protocol. They actually are using this symmetric a
lot, right, so that's their application.
However, with symmetric, it only guarantees confidentiality
itself, OK, itself, but if you combine that symmetric with something else,
you might have the other security goal achieved,
right? And also you need to make sure the security key,
OK, in symmetric crypto is securely exchanged.
So if key got disclosed, and there's no secrecy at all,
right? And for CBC mode, um, IV number also
needs to be exchanged securely. And then,
but there are some scenario as we as we explained at the
beginning, and we want to have authenticity,
we want to have the integrity, we want to have the non-repudiation,
right? And what should we do, right? The symmetric
itself doesn't solve any of this issue, OK?
It doesn't get any of this goal achieved.
So we got to find something else to be added to this symmetric so that
we have some better protection for our system,
right? And for symmetric key encryption,
there is also an issue, which is key exhaustion.
Here's what I mean here, right? So, if, for example,
we want to, uh, we want to have this two party to
secretly talk to each other, we got to make sure they have one key,
right? And then if there's a third party,
and the C and A, they want to discuss secretly,
and B and C, they also want to have another secret conversation and then
a different key, OK? There are 3 keys needed,
right, by each two parties. If there are 44 parties
here, right? And then so D and A needs to have
one key, which is different from other keys.
DB has to have one, DC has to have one, right?
So, in total, there are 6 keys for 6, for,
for 4 parties here, right? If there are 5
parties and each 2 parties want to um
I mean, have a secret conversation. How many keys do we need?
We need 10 keys in total, which actually equals this
number. Um, 5 parties times
4 divided by 2, which is 10 in total. So
that formula give us, give us when we have n parties,
and in this N parties, we want every two parties to have a secret
communication. Right, and then we need that number
of keys. Right, we need that number of keys.
So this makes this scenario not, um, the symmetric not scalable
to this scenario, right? So you got to find that number of keys and
also remember you got to find someone which can
securely, um I'm sorry, securely. Share the
key between each two parties and there must be some
key distribution center right and there is some uh original
architecture or protocol they actually apply the key distribution center but
that's under the assumption there is one,
right, but who can be that key distribution center.
Right? And whether it's government or whether it's a
trustworthy um party, big company,
Anyway, we have to find the one, right, to oversee all parties'
communication and distribute those keys.
And what if that trustworthy um external party,
um, has all the key and he can also hear all
your conversation, right, clearly, because he has all the keys,
right? Those are the symmetric key. Remember that the same key can be
done for the encryption and can also be used for decryption,
right? So there's another party which oversee all
this conversation, right? So, so it's not
applicable, right, in the reality. So why Why,
yeah, we have, have probably run out of key,
right? And then we also have to guarantee there is someone who can generate those keys to distribute
to each party safely, right? So this makes this symmetric
encryption, um, not applicable to many cases.
And then you can also imagine we have eBay and Amazon nowadays,
right? And in those um online shopping scenario,
if we have millions of customers, and if Amazon wants to talk
to each of his customers securely, secretly,
right? Amazon has to generate one key for his customer,
which where the key must be different from other customers.
So that means Amazon has to maintain millions of millions of
Encryption key and decryptate the, the symmetric key,
right? So Amazon has to generate that millions of keys for
his customer to use, right? So which makes that
not um symmetric key encryption here, not
scalable and not say, not, not, not
actually um applicable to the cases here,
right? And if we only have the symmetric key encryption.
Uh, and then we probably won't have eBay or Amazon.
Nowadays, right, so only after people have found a way to use
asymmetric, asymmetric, which means encryption key and decryption key are
different, and then people found um. Amazon
and eBay, they are boosting. OK, they, they have been such a
big company having millions of the customers,
OK, because asymmetric key, asymmetric crypto has been
developed. OK, uh, about 20 years ago. Otherwise,
people found there's no way, right, to have the current nowadays,
Amazon or eBay. So that's why, um, we will also focus
on asymmetric next week and we'll talk about how asymmetric
encryption and decryption is working. And I've already made a pre-lecture
recording uh for RSA DDH algorithm available.
So if you got time, please do watch them before my next lecture
because in my next lecture, I'll focus on the application.
I won't discuss how those algorithm works uh one more time in my lecture
because we will run out of time. So that's about next week.
And then you will now, you will then learn how those different um
encryption way in asymmetric crypto can work
better to keep the authenticity
and um yeah, combined with some other algorithm integrating as well.
And then also non-repudiation, OK? That's how asymmetric
encryption can help, OK? These are all the
algorithm which were based on Asymmetric.
OK, so in asymmetric there is no key distribution center
needed as what we need for symmetric, right,
and scalable to any size of network, which is why we
have eBay and Amazon in such a big scale,
right? And the keys for encryption and decryption are different,
OK, so that's what we will learn next week.
OK. So that's all for today. Um, thank you.
If you do have any other questions, you can stay in this room or if you pop up
with some questions later, you can always use Teams to discuss.
And we'll learn more, OK, in the workshop,
you'll also get to practice all this uh encryption and decryption algorithm,
OK. Uh, we do have a quiz this week, um,
so the access code. It will be given in your workshop.
If you didn't attend the workshop, I'll,
I'll make an announcement with an access code online.
So, and also attached to your actual quiz,
so you can get the access code and you can do your quiz.
But just some reminder, um, if you're not ready,
do not open your quiz yet and try practice a bit more,
um, with our workshop activity. And then you move to a quiz,
you all have just one attempt, um, but each attempt,
I mean, your, your attempt, your only attempt will have 3 hours.
So you can go through it. It's the time wise it's more than enough.
It's just a few questions in your quiz. But yeah,
in those 3 hours, you, you better like do some practice and finish all
those questions, OK, in one go, everyone just has 1 attempt.
OK? Thank you.